Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we have a special lesson for all of you who are looking for a new apartment
今天，我们为所有正在找新公寓
or house.
或房子的人准备了一节特别的课。
Or even if you're not looking for an apartment, this lesson will be useful because it can
即使你不在找公寓，这节课也很有用，因为它能
help you describe what your current apartment or house looks like.
帮你描述你现在住的公寓或房子是什么样子。
That's right.
没错。
So we're going to be describing an apartment and other vocabulary related to apartment
所以我们要描述公寓以及和找公寓
hunting.
相关的其他词汇。
Let's take a look at some of the first words that we have in Vocabulary Preview.
我们先来看看词汇预览中的一些单词。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
We're going to hear these two words in the dialogue.
我们会在对话中听到这两个词。
The first one is landlord.
第一个是房东。
Landlord.
房东。
All right.
好的。
So who is a landlord or what is a landlord?
那么谁是房东，或者房东是什么？
Well it's pretty simple.
嗯，这很简单。
A landlord is the person who owns the house.
房东就是拥有房子的人。
Okay.
好的。
Or apartment.
或者公寓。
So the owner of the house.
所以是房子的主人。
Right.
对。
And the landlord rents out the apartment to the tenants.
房东把公寓租给租客。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
Tenants.
租客。
So the tenants are the people that are renting the apartment or house.
所以租客就是租公寓或房子的人。
Exactly.
没错。
Two important words that we'll find in the dialogue.
对话中会出现的两个重要词汇。
Tenants and landlord.
租客和房东。
So why don't we take a listen to the dialogue now and we'll hear as a couple is checking
那我们为什么不现在听听对话呢？我们会听到一对夫妇在查看
out a new apartment.
一套新公寓。
Hi.
你好。
We are the Christiansons.
我们是克里斯蒂安森一家。
We're here to see the apartment.
我们是来看公寓的。
Oh hi.
哦，你好。
Sure.
当然。
Come on in.
请进。
Well as you can see the place has just been renovated.
嗯，你们看，这地方刚翻新过。
The previous tenants left a huge mess here so the landlord has redone everything.
之前的租客把这里弄得一团糟，所以房东重新装修了所有东西。
It looks great.
看起来很棒。
It's so bright and airy.
这么明亮通风。
What great light.
光线真好。
I really love these hardwood floors.
我真的很喜欢这些硬木地板。
What's the square footage of this place?
这地方的面积是多少平方英尺？
Well it's about 120 square meters or 1300 square feet more or less.
嗯，大概120平方米，或者1300平方英尺左右。
Oh the landlord has also installed new kitchen appliances.
哦，房东还安装了新的厨房电器。
There's a new dishwasher and a professional grade gas range.
有新的洗碗机和专业级燃气灶。
Really at this price this place is an amazing deal.
真的吗？以这个价格，这地方真是超值。
I love it.
我喜欢。
But wait.
但是等等。
What are the payment terms?
付款条件是什么？
First and last month rent as deposit and rent is due on the first of every month.
押金是第一个月和最后一个月的租金，租金在每个月的第一天支付。
Considering the amount of money invested into the apartment it's a very good deal.
考虑到投入这套公寓的资金，这已经很划算了。
Yes it is.
是的。
Too good to be true.
好得难以置信。
The living room and dining room are quite spacious as you can see and down this hall
客厅和餐厅很宽敞，你们能看到，沿着这条走廊
here's the master bedroom.
就是主卧室。
It has a huge walk in closet and an en suite bathroom.
它有一个巨大的步入式衣帽间和一间套内浴室。
We can't go in there yet as the police, I mean the clean up crew hasn't finished yet.
我们现在还不能进去，因为警察，我是说清洁队还没完成。
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
What's in here?
里面有什么？
Alright so apparently the apartment was too good to be true.
好吧，显然这套公寓好得难以置信。
Yeah I don't think that's exactly what they were expecting to find in the bathroom.
是啊，我觉得那可不是他们期望在浴室里找到的东西。
Okay well we did find a lot of great words and phrases so why don't we take a look at
好的，我们确实找到了很多很棒的词汇和短语，所以我们现在来看看
that now in Language Takeaway.
语言要点部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
We're just gonna look at a bunch of vocabulary items related to apartments and house hunting.
我们只看一些和公寓及找房相关的词汇。
So we've got a lot to cover here so let's get started with the first one.
所以我们要讲很多内容，让我们从第一个开始。
Renovated.
翻新过的。
Okay so the verb to renovate.
好的，所以动词是翻新。
Great word and I think some examples will help us understand the meaning.
很棒的词，我觉得一些例子能帮我们理解意思。
Example 1.
例子一。
I had to renovate my kitchen because I accidentally burned everything while cooking.
我不得不翻新我的厨房，因为做饭时不小心烧了所有东西。
Example 2.
例子二。
The city recently renovated the ceiling of the local church.
城市最近翻新了当地教堂的天花板。
Example 3.
例子三。
John is planning on renovating his nightclub so as to make it more modern.
约翰计划翻新他的夜总会，让它更现代。
Okay so basically to renovate means to make new again.
好的，所以基本上翻新就是重新变新。
Right, when you renovate a house or an apartment you take everything down and build it back
对，当你翻新房子或公寓时，你把所有东西拆掉，然后重新
up again.
建起来。
Okay so it's usually only used for buildings, for apartments, for houses.
好的，所以通常只用于建筑、公寓、房子。
Or offices.
或者办公室。
You don't say you renovate your computer.
你不会说翻新你的电脑。
Yep and also when you just do something really simple like change the paint color, that's
是的，而且当你只做一些很简单的事，比如换油漆颜色，那
not a renovation.
不是翻新。
That's redecoration.
那是重新装饰。
When you renovate you have to like you know use a hammer and saw and lots of tools.
当你翻新时，你得用锤子和锯子以及很多工具。
Change a lot.
改变很多。
Yep.
是的。
Okay so the apartment was newly renovated and it was bright and airy.
好的，所以公寓是新翻新的，而且明亮通风。
Airy.
通风的。
Alright so airy, well I guess we understand the word air, right?
好的，通风，我想我们理解空气这个词，对吧？
So if an apartment or something is airy.
所以如果公寓或什么东西是通风的。
It has lots of space.
它有很多空间。
Lots of place to move around.
很多可以移动的地方。
Okay so it's wide, it's...
好的，所以它很宽敞，它...
It's open.
它是开放的。
It's open, okay.
它是开放的，好的。
An open apartment.
一个开放的公寓。
Very good.
非常好。
Now for our next word, an important question she asked for the square footage.
现在看下一个词，她问了一个重要问题，关于平方英尺。
Square footage.
平方英尺。
The square footage of the apartment.
公寓的平方英尺。
Okay so we know square foot, right?
好的，我们知道平方英尺，对吧？
So feet like a measure of space.
所以英尺是一种空间度量。
Right.
对。
The square footage is just basically the area, how big.
平方英尺基本上就是面积，有多大。
Okay so why don't we listen to some examples of how we can use these two words square footage
好的，那我们为什么不听一些例子，看看怎么在句子中使用这两个词平方英尺
in a sentence.
呢？
Example one.
例子一。
As a civil engineer I have to calculate the square footage of the construction site.
作为一名土木工程师，我必须计算建筑工地的平方英尺。
Example two.
例子二。
Robert is worried that the square footage of this land is not big enough.
罗伯特担心这块地的平方英尺不够大。
Example three.
例子三。
If you multiply the width of the room by the length you will have the square footage of
如果你把房间的宽度乘以长度，你就会得到房间的平方英尺
the room.
。
Those are some great examples and I find this, the ending of this word, edge, footage, it's
这些例子很棒，我发现这个词的结尾，age，footage，很
interesting isn't it?
有趣，不是吗？
Yeah I guess you can only use it with the imperial system.
是的，我想你只能在英制单位中使用它。
So you can also say tonnage, so how big, how heavy, or mileage.
所以你也可以说吨位，表示多大、多重，或者里程。
But you can't say, for example in meters, you wouldn't say meterage.
但你不能说，比如用米，你不会说米age。
No you can't say that.
不，你不能那么说。
So it's not for the metric system, it's only for some units of measurement in the imperial
所以它不用于公制系统，只用于英制系统中的一些
system.
度量单位。
Exactly.
没错。
Alright so after we've measured the square footage of the apartment, we saw that they
好的，在我们测量了公寓的平方英尺之后，我们看到他们有新的
had new appliances.
电器。
Appliances.
Appliance.
电器。
So kitchen appliances, what are those?
所以厨房电器，那些是什么？
Machines that do stuff in the kitchen.
在厨房里做事的机器。
Alright so a blender, a stove, a microwave.
好的，所以搅拌机、炉子、微波炉。
Yep.
是的。
Or I can say electric appliances.
或者我可以说电器。
So like your TV, an iron, a vacuum cleaner.
比如你的电视、熨斗、吸尘器。
Okay, so appliance can be any type of machine that's used.
好的，所以电器可以是任何类型的机器，用于
In a house.
房子里。
Yep.
是的。
And well one of these appliances was a professional grade gas range.
嗯，其中一个电器是专业级燃气灶。
Okay this is a great phrase and I want to break it down.
好的，这是一个很棒的短语，我想分解一下。
So a gas range, now this is basically a stove, right?
所以燃气灶，这基本上就是一个炉子，对吧？
Okay.
好的。
That uses gas instead of electricity.
使用燃气而不是电。
So I can have an electric range.
所以我可以用电灶。
Exactly.
没错。
And professional grade, this is something that's really high quality.
而专业级，这是指质量很高的东西。
So if it's high quality, why do we say it's professional grade?
如果质量高，为什么我们说它是专业级？
Because it's so good that professionals use it.
因为它好到专业人士都在用。
Okay, so can I only have professional grade kitchen appliances?
好的，所以我只能有专业级厨房电器吗？
No, of course not.
不，当然不是。
You can have a professional grade anything, like a professional grade carpet for example.
你可以有专业级的任何东西，比如专业级地毯。
Okay, or a professional grade pickup truck.
好的，或者专业级皮卡。
Or you can even change this a little bit and say industrial grade.
或者你甚至可以稍微改一下，说工业级。
So after we've seen all the appliances, they describe the house as spacious.
所以在我们看了所有电器之后，他们描述房子很宽敞。
Spacious.
宽敞的。
The house is very spacious.
房子很宽敞。
Pretty easy.
很简单。
We know the word space here, right?
我们知道空间这个词，对吧？
Right.
对。
So obviously this means lots of space.
所以显然这意味着有很多空间。
It has lots of space.
它有很多空间。
Yeah.
是的。
So I guess maybe spacious and airy are a little bit similar, right?
所以我想也许宽敞和通风有点相似，对吧？
Okay.
好的。
And of course, once we were in the master bedroom, we saw that they had a walk-in closet.
当然，一旦我们进了主卧室，我们看到他们有一个步入式衣帽间。
A walk-in closet.
步入式衣帽间。
Walk-in closet.
A walk-in closet.
步入式衣帽间。
Right, so this is very easy.
对，这很简单。
I guess walk-in.
我想步入式。
You can walk into it.
你可以走进去。
Right.
对。
And so it's a huge closet, right?
所以它是一个巨大的衣帽间，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
Now just a note on the spelling here.
现在注意一下拼写。
Walk-in or hyphenated.
Walk-in 或带连字符。
Okay.
好的。
Walk-in closet.
步入式衣帽间。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
Very good.
非常好。
And apart from this beautiful closet, we had an en suite bathroom.
除了这个漂亮的衣帽间，我们还有一个套内浴室。
En suite bathroom.
套内浴室。
Right.
对。
Another note on the spelling here.
另一个拼写注意点。
It's E-N.
是E-N。
Right.
对。
Hyphen.
连字符。
S-U-I-T-E.
S-U-I-T-E。
So even though it's E-N, we pronounce it like an O-N.
所以尽管是E-N，我们发音像O-N。
Yep.
是的。
En suite.
套房。
So an en suite bathroom is a bathroom inside the room.
所以套间浴室就是房间内的浴室。
Okay, inside the master bedroom.
好的，在主卧室内。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
Very good.
非常好。
En suite bathroom.
套间浴室。
So a lot of great words describing the apartment and also other aspects of real estate.
所以有很多好词来描述公寓以及房地产的其他方面。
So why don't we listen to these one more time in context and we'll see how they fit together
那我们不如再听一遍这些词在语境中的用法，看看它们如何组合在一起
to describe an apartment.
来描述一套公寓。
Hi, we are the Christiansons.
嗨，我们是克里斯蒂安森一家。
We're here to see the apartment.
我们是来看公寓的。
Oh, hi.
哦，嗨。
Sure.
当然。
Come on in.
请进。
Well, as you can see, the place has just been renovated.
嗯，如你们所见，这地方刚翻新过。
The previous tenants left a huge mess here, so the landlord has redone everything.
之前的租户把这里弄得一团糟，所以房东重新装修了所有东西。
It looks great.
看起来很棒。
It's so bright and airy.
这里又明亮又通风。
What great light.
光线真好。
I really love these hardwood floors.
我真的很喜欢这些硬木地板。
What's the square footage of this place?
这地方有多少平方英尺？
Well, it's about 120 square meters or 1,300 square feet, more or less.
嗯，大约120平方米，或者说1300平方英尺，差不多。
Oh, the landlord has also installed new kitchen appliances.
哦，房东还安装了新的厨房电器。
There's a new dishwasher and a professional-grade gas range.
有一台新洗碗机和一台专业级燃气灶。
Really at this price, this place is an amazing deal.
真的，以这个价格，这地方真是超值。
I love it.
我喜欢。
But wait, what are the payment terms?
但是等等，付款条件是什么？
First and last month rent as deposit and rent is due on the first of every month.
押金是第一个月和最后一个月的租金，租金每月一号付。
Considering the amount of money invested into the apartment, it's a very good deal.
考虑到投入在这套公寓上的钱，这很划算。
Yes, it is.
是的，确实。
Too good to be true.
好得令人难以置信。
The living room and dining room are quite spacious, as you can see.
客厅和餐厅相当宽敞，如你们所见。
And down this hall, here's the master bedroom.
沿着这条走廊，这里是主卧室。
It has a huge walk-in closet and an en suite bathroom.
它有一个巨大的步入式衣帽间和一个套间浴室。
We can't go in there yet as the police, uh, I mean, the cleanup crew hasn't finished yet.
我们还不能进去，因为警察，呃，我是说，清洁队还没完成。
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
What's in here?
这里面有什么？
Alright, so this is always kind of difficult to look for a new apartment and to go and
好吧，找新公寓和去看房总是有点难
see them.
的。
But it's interesting here, they were renting and they had a real estate agent.
但有趣的是，这里他们在租房，而且有房产中介。
Yeah, um, and actually this is very uncommon in America, isn't it?
是的，嗯，实际上这在美国很不常见，对吧？
Yeah, I guess you don't really use a real estate agent unless you're going to buy a
是的，我想除非你要买房子或公寓，否则你不会真的用房产中介
house or apartment.
。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
So when you're renting, you just go and look by yourself.
所以租房时，你就自己去看。
Right.
对。
You can find ads in the newspaper, on the internet and deal directly with the landlord.
你可以在报纸、网上找广告，直接和房东打交道。
Right.
对。
So after you've done your house hunting and found your apartment, um, you got to set up
所以在你找房并找到公寓后，嗯，你得设定
the payment conditions.
付款条件。
Right.
对。
Like we saw in the dialogue, the payment terms were first and last month's rent as deposit.
就像我们在对话中看到的，付款条件是第一个月和最后一个月的租金作为押金。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
And that's basically, they'll keep that just in case you damage something in the apartment.
基本上，他们会留着那笔钱，以防你在公寓里损坏东西。
Or have a monster living in your bathroom.
或者浴室里住着怪物。
Exactly.
没错。
And another thing is that I've noticed in some countries you pay rent in advance.
另一件事是我注意到在一些国家，你提前付租金。
Right.
对。
So in America, you only pay one month's rent at a time, right?
所以在美国，你一次只付一个月的租金，对吧？
Right.
对。
So I guess this is an interesting topic, real estate and apartment hunting and renting is
所以我想这是个有趣的话题，房地产、找房和租房在
different in different countries.
不同国家是不同的。
So that's where you guys need to come and tell us how is, how does this work in your
所以这就是你们需要来告诉我们，在你们国家
country?
这是怎么运作的？
You can also use some of the vocabulary in this dialogue to tell us about your apartment.
你也可以用这个对话中的一些词汇来告诉我们你的公寓。
Right.
对。
How many rooms do you have?
你有几个房间？
Bedrooms, dining rooms?
卧室、餐厅？
What's the square footage?
面积是多少平方英尺？
Exactly.
没错。
Or how many square meters, right?
或者多少平方米，对吧？
Yep.
是的。
So check out our website, EnglishPod.com.
所以请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好的。
And we'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里见你们。
Thanks for listening and until next time, goodbye.
感谢收听，下次再见，拜拜。